Guide to the Linewaiters' Gazette Collection BCMS.0027
Brooklyn Collection
Linewaiters' Gazette Collection
1973-2019
Brooklyn Collection
Park Slope Food Coop
BCMS.0027
14.7 Linear Feet in 10 document boxes and 12 flat boxes
A collection of issues of the Linewaiters' Gazette, a bimonthly newsletter published by members of the Park Slope Food Coop (PSFC).
Historical Note
The Linewaiters' Gazette is a publication produced by the membership of the Park Slope Food Coop, a cooperative grocery store at 782 Union Street in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn. The Coop was founded in 1973 as a member-owned and operated store; members provide the labor to run the store and in exchange may shop for goods with a lower price markup than in typical grocery stores. This cooperative model encourages and depends on member engagement with all aspects of operations and the pages of the Gazette reflect this member involvement with business decision making. General meeting notices, calls for boycotts, and debates over policies appear frequently and show, over time, the development of the Coop from a small collective to a membership of more than 16,000.
Related Materials
Digital copies of the Linewaiters' Gazette from October 7, 1999 through the present can be found on the Park Slope Food Coop's website: https://www.foodcoop.com/
Scope and Contents
This collection contains original copies and reprints of the Linewaiters' Gazette newsletter as collected by the Park Slope Food Coop staff. Several issues are missing; notably, from 1982, 1985, 1991, and 1994 (Volumes C, F, L, and O, respectively), and there are no issues from 2002 (Volume W). There is only one issue after 2006, from May 2019. Ancillary materials like building plans, spin-off newsletters, and product lists are also included in the collection and noted in the inventory below. An index covering the period from January 1983 to March 1987 is also included.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Linewaiters' Gazette Collection up to 1994 was donated to the Brooklyn Collection in April of 2013. Issues from 1994-2019 accrued at later dates.
Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by volume. Each biweekly issue within a volume is housed in its own folder. The Linewaiters' Gazette did not start using the volume/number system for the paper until 1980, so early issues from 1973-1979 are gathered together in one section.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Boxes 6-22 in this collection are currently unavailable for research. Please reach out to the Center for Brooklyn History for further information.
Cooperation -- History; Cooperative Societies -- United States; Cooperative Societies -- United States -- Management; Food cooperatives; Grocery trade; Natural foods industry--United States; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Park Slope Historic District (New York, N.Y.)
- Early issues, September 22, 1973 - December 27, 1979. (Box 1, Box 2)
  General
  This section also includes an expansion plan (1976), resignation announcement (1978), Renovation Rag No. 3 (March 1979), and "The Future Revealed" (1979).
- Volume A, January 10 - December 18, 1980. (Box 3)
- Volume B, January 2 - December 31, 1981. (Box 3)
- Volume C, January 21 - November 25, 1982. (Box 3)
- Volume D, January 13 - December 22, 1983. (Box 4)
  This sections also includes an index of Gazette articles from January 1983 - March 1987.
- Volume E, January - April, 1984. (Box 4)
- Volume E, May - December, 1984. (Box 5)
- Volume F, c. mid-June, 1985. (Box 5)
- Volume G, January 16 - December 25, 1986. (Box 5)
- Volume H, January 15 - May 21, 1987. (Box 5)
- Volume H, May 28 - December 31, 1987. (Box 6 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
  This section also includes "Food News," May 28, 1987.
- Volume I, January 14 - December 29, 1988. (Box 6 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
  This section also includes "Food News," March 9, 1988.
- Volume J, January 1989. (Box 6 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume J, February - December, 1989. (Box 7 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume K, January 11 - July 26, 1990. (Box 7 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume K, August - December, 1990. (Box 8 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume L, May 30 and November 28, 1991. (Box 8 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume M, January 9 - November 12, 1992. (Box 8 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume M, November 26 - December 26, 1992. (Box 9 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume N, January 7 - September 2, 1993. (Box 9 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume N, September 19 - December 23, 1993. (Box 10 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume O, January 6 - June 9, 1994. (Box 10 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume O, June 23 - December 22, 1994. (Box 11 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume P, January 5 - December 25, 1995. (Box 12 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume Q, January 4 - December 19, 1996. (Box 13 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume R, January 2 - December 18, 1997. (Box 14 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume S, January 1 - December 31, 1998. (Box 15 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
  This section also includes "Final Report of the Location Study Committee," January 15, 1998.
- Volume T, January 14 - December 30, 1999. (Box 16 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume U, January 13 - December 28, 2000. (Box 17 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume V, January - December, 2001. (Box 18 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume X, January - December, 2003. (Box 19 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume Y, January - December, 2004. (Box 20 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume Z, January - December, 2005. (Box 21 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume AA, January - December, 2006. (Box 22 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])
- Volume NN, May 9, 2019. (Box 22 [TEMPORARILY UNAVAILABLE])